<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Handsons on Datadog Training Site</title>
    <link>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Handsons on Datadog Training Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 08:47:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Datadog 101 - Monitoring 101</title>
      <link>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/monitoring101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/monitoring101/</guid>
      <description>Everyone should get login information for a Datadog account they can use for this session. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t received this information (and you are here in the room with us), contact the instructors. This will include a username and password for a Datadog account, as well as the IP Address for the load balancer of your cluster of servers.
 Login to your Demo Datadog Account. Note: Use this demo even if you have the credentials for your company&amp;rsquo;s account since it has been setup to collect data from the demo environment Navigate to the Metrics Explorer (https://app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datadog 101 - Building Great Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/buildinggreatdashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/buildinggreatdashboards/</guid>
      <description>First Dashboard  From the menu, return to the dashboard you created earlier. Drag and drop a timeseries widget onto the first well on the canvas. Notice that you can change the visualization at any time without having to drag another widget on the canvas. In the first textbox under Choose metrics and events, select elasticsearch.primaries.search.query.current. Notice that the textbox supports a fuzzy search so i can enter elseapriseaqc and get to the right metric much more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Docker</title>
      <link>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/monitordocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 08:47:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datadog.github.io/summit-training-session/handson/monitordocker/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring on Docker This exercise requires Docker to be installed somewhere. You could do this on your laptop, on a Vagrant box, or on a cloud provider. If installing for the first time visit https://store.docker.com/search?type=edition&amp;amp;offering=community to get it setup.
 Navigate to the Agent Installation page in the Datadog application (https://app.datadoghq.com/account/settings#agent/docker). Select Docker and copy the first command. Run it where ever you have Docker installed. You now have the Datadog agent running on your Docker machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>